Guide to the Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater Records, 1934-1994 CTC.1981.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater Records
1934-1994
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Playhouse
CTC.1981.01
99 Linear Feet (167 document boxes, 35 oversize pressbooks, 4 scrapbooks, and 5 oversize photograph albums)
This collection consists of the records of the Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater, including operational files, business records, correspondence, press clippings, photographs, negatives, scripts, programs, posters, scrapbooks, press releases, and brochures. These materials relate to the activities of the Pittsburgh Playhouse, including the School of the Theatre, Playhouse Jr., American Conservatory Theatre, Vanguard Theatre, Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, American Dance Ensemble, Point Park College, and the restaurant and banquet facilities. For the most part, these records are from the time period before the Pittsburgh Playhouse came under the operation of Point Park College.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Production and General Files
Series II. Business and Financial Records
Series III. Photographs and Negatives
Series IV. Programs
Series V. Pressbooks, Clippings, Brochures and Press Releases
Series VI. Scripts/Production Books
Series VII. Addendum 1
Series VIII. Addendum 2
History
The Pittsburgh Playhouse, a community theatre company, was created to fill the desire for a resident theatre left behind by the collapse of commercial venues. Motion pictures impacted live theater and forced stock companies and other theatre companies to lose their grip on the Depression Era's rare entertainment dollar. Pittsburgh's stock companies, like the George Sharp Players (Shubert and Alvin Theatres, 1927-31) or the Nixon Players (Nixon Theatre) featured a diverse fare of light comedies, farce, melodramas, and mystery but still could not meet the tastes, prices, or choices available in films. The only options remaining were the large-scale touring companies (also a dwindling possibility with the conversion of the Alvin to a motion picture format in 1932), burlesque or small local ventures. Despite attempts by the Pittsburgh Civic Playhouse, Pittsburgh Summer Theatre, and other theatre groups, little opportunity existed for Pittsburgh's residents to create and produce theatre outside the university setting.
In 1934, a group of civic leaders joined forces to form a resident community theatre -- The Pittsburgh Playhouse Association. The financial and artistic stability provided by an affluent Executive board which was complemented by an Advisory committee (including local theatre professionals), gave the new venture a strong foundation and a community impulse from which to start. The new community theatre was contributing to civic culture and developing the talents of avocational actors. The first production, Art and Mrs. Bottle, opened in a borrowed auditorium at the Frick School and rented equipment on December 10, 1934, to social fanfare and mixed reviews. Despite a lack of permanent home and financial hard times, the recipe for a long-lived institution had been established -- wealthy patrons, knowledgeable artistic guidance and popular appeal. By the second Season in 1935, a part-time Artistic Director was replaced with a full-time position and a permanent home in the Hamlet Theater on Craft Avenue was renovated and available. Despite a briefly lived (1935-37) movement away from semi-professionals toward a professional company under its first Director, Herbert Gellendre, the organization remained committed to a semi-professional, community theater under its next Director, Fred Burleigh, for the next thirty years.
Although briefly interrupted by World War II, the Playhouse offered a varied and popular fare under Mr. Burleigh's leadership. The expanding cultural and social center was complete with a restaurant offering meals and entertainment both prior and post performances for the membership. The greatest era of growth occurred in the late 1940's with the addition of the school and children's theater. In 1947 the Playhouse began offering classes in all aspects of the theatre, formalizing the Playhouse tradition of hands-on learning. The school offered a full-time curriculum including stage techniques, radio acting, and other subjects related to theatre taught by instructors that included Edith Skinner, Shirley Jones, Sada Thompson, George Peppard, Charles Grodin, and local personalities like Helen Wayne Rauh. The second important component was the addition of a children's theatre. In 1949, Fred Burleigh approached staff member, William Leech, to organize the Playhouse Junior. Mr. Leech quickly found success with the shared use of the available acting and production talents and the development of original scripts, mostly from extant sources. Both elements reflected and enhanced the Playhouse's local reputation for quality theatre.
The period of growth continued into the 1950's and included the addition of two theatres (Craft Avenue in 1952 and Theatre Upstairs in 1958). This growth, supported by box office sales and private donations, lead to ambitious thoughts of professionalism. Unfortunately, by the early 1960's, the recent expansions and size of the organization, as well as waning public interest caused an increasing amount of fiscal distress. The decision was made to enter into a joint venture with Carnegie Tech (now Carnegie Mellon University) to help regain a somewhat tarnished reputation and fulfill the goal of creating a first rate professional theater. In 1965, William Ball formed a professional company called The American Conservatory Theater which resided at the Pittsburgh Playhouse. After a somewhat successful, albeit short, six month season, Mr. Ball and the Pittsburgh Playhouse parted company. The American Conservatory Theater A.C.T. thereafter settled in San Francisco and remains a major regional company and training ground. In order to further the goal of professionalizing the theater, the Pittsburgh Playhouse introduced John Hancock as the Director during the 1966-1967 season. The intellectual style of Mr. Hancock's theater, although of respectable quality, was met with disinterest by an audience weaned on light comedy and musical revues. Mr. Hancock quickly moved on.
By the late 1960's the Pittsburgh Playhouse was financially strapped and still unsuccessful in meeting the goal of professionalization. Collaboration with Point Park College managed to keep the doors to the Pittsburgh Playhouse open for a few more years and during this time the Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre and the American Dance Ensemble were formed, but even that arrangement proved unworkable. The Executive Committee voted to disband and close the Pittsburgh Playhouse complex in 1973. The joint venture with Point Park College was unable to sustain the distressed institution, however; Point Park acquired the Pittsburgh Playhouse facilities to expand their performing arts departments. From 1974 to the 1990's, Point Park continued the Playhouse tradition of performing arts education and until recently maintained the film repertory, children's theatre and the small professional company. Due to financial constraints, Point Park College discontinued the film series and severely curtailed the children's and professional companies.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists of the records of the Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater, including operational files, business records, correspondence, press clippings, photographs, negatives, scripts, programs, posters, scrapbooks, press releases, and brochures relating to the activities of the Pittsburgh Playhouse, including the School of the Theatre, Playhouse Jr., American Conservatory Theatre, Vanguard Theatre, Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, American Dance Ensemble, Point Park College, and the restaurant and banquet facilities. Also included are scrapbooks documenting the activities of Irene Kaufmann Settlement, Children's Civic Theatre Society, Pittsburgh Civic Playhouse, Snatched From the Noose: A Melodrama (Fort Pitt Hotel, 1936), Pittsburgh Little Theatre, and Pittsburgh Summer Playhouse.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Helen Wayne Rauh and Richard Rauh in 1981. Additional materials were donated in August, 2000.
Previous Citation
Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater Records, 1934-1994, CTC.1981.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater Records, 1934-1973, CTC.25, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Financial records; Programs (Documents); Photographs; Negatives (Photographic); Clippings (Information artifacts); Press releases; Brochures; Business records; Realia; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Theater; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Community theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Point Park College; American Dance Ensemble; Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre; Vanguard Theatre; American Conservatory Theater; Playhouse Jr.; Pittsburgh Playhouse. School of the Theater; Pittsburgh Playhouse
- Production and General Files, 1934-1974; I.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains the office files, correspondence, minutes, memoranda, membership and subscription logs, and stage managers reports for the operation of the theaters, school and restaurant. The files are arranged in alphabetical order by folder title. At the end of the series there is a small amount of oversize materials.
  - Actors' Equity Association - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Actors' Equity Association - Memoranda, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Actors' Equity Association - Non-Professional affidavits, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Addendum to June 1955 Parking and Economic (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administration office map (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Admissions/Receipts totals, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advertising orders, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Advising assignments (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - After the Fall - Notes and memos (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amahl and the Night Visitors - Notes and memos (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Cast lists (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Conservatory Theater - William Ball (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Beyond the Fringe (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Brochures (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Charley's Aunt (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Death of a Salesman (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Cut Lines for Press Photos (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Foundation (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Noah (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Rose Tattoo (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Six Characters in Search of an Author (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Souvenir Program (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Summary of Joint Venture Between Carnegie Institute of Technology and the Pittsburgh Playhouse (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Television Copy (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Theater Clock Schedules (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Conservatory Theater - Tiny Alice (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Amusement tax, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Anything Goes - Notes and memos (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Applications for Employment, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Applications for Employment - Inactive, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Applications for Employment - Stage Managers, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Applications for Employment - Director/Producer, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Arms and the Man - Notes and memos (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Attendance reports, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Audience development, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Audience survey, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Audit Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Audit Reports - Carnegie Tech/Playhouse Company, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Audit Reports, 1963-1966 [Incomplete] (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Audit Reports, 1945-1957 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
  - Ballet Jr. - Schedules and notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Barefoot in the Park - Notes and memos (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Biographies - A (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Biographies - American Conservatory Theatre (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Biographies - B-D (Box 5, Folder 5-7)
  - Biographies - E-P (Box 6, Folder 1-12)
  - Biographies - Q-Z (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  - Board of Trustees - Annual meeting agendas, 1959-1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees - Financial report, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees - Members, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees - Minutes and correspondence, 1967-1974 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
  - Board of Trustees - Minutes, 1959-1964 (Box 8, Volume 1-4)
  - Board of Trustees - Minutes, 1952-1959 (Box 9, Volume 1-4)
  - Board of Trustees - Minutes, 1934-1952 (Box 10, Volume 1-4)
  - Booth, Marshall (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Born Yesterday - Notes and memos (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Borrowed Production Materials -- Loan Agreements, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Boys in the Band - Notes and memos (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Brave Little Tailor - Notes and memos (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Bucci Detective Agency (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Brockett and Barbara Upstairs - Notes and memos (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Burrelle's Press Clipping Bureau (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Building and equipment values (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Cactus Flower - Notes and memos (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Campaign to Industry, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Campaign, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Capital Needs - Plans A and B, 1968-1972 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Carmel Presbyterian Church Property (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Carousel - Notes and memos (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Cash Flow Projections, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Children's Theater Tour, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Cinderella - Notes and memos (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Classroom "D" scheduling, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Community and audience development (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Continuity of Professional Theater - A proposal by Robert Novak, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Contracts, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
  - Contracts, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Contracts - Operating engineers, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Contributions, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Corporate Pitch - Friedman proposal (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1967 (Box 11, Folder 28-29)
  - Charter of the Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater (Box 12, Volume 1)
  - Correspondence - Actors, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Art Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Automatic Retailers of America, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Frederick Burleigh, 1963-1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Names Beginning with B-C, 1963-1967 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence - Carnegie Tech, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Civic Board, 1960-1965 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Executive Board, 1960-1968 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Names Beginning with F, 1963-1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Films, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Finance Committee, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Fundraising, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Golden Crucible, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Name Beginning with H-L, 1963-1967 (Box 14, Folder 5-9)
  - Correspondence - Laurel Foundation, 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Name Beginning with M, 1963-1967 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Management Applicants, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Mellon National Bank, 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Membership Drives, 1967-1971 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Name Beginning with N, 1963-1967 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - New York Department of Labor, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Name Beginning with O-P, 1963-1967 (Box 14, Folder 17-18)
  - Correspondence - Pittsburgh Foundation, 1961-1967 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Play Agents [Other than Samuel French], 1963-1967 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Playhouse Plus [Volunteer Organization] (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Playwrights, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Production Staff, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Name Beginning with R, 1963-1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Samuel French, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Stage Lighting, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Surnames/Corporate Name Beginning with W, 1963-1967 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1968-1974 (Box 15, Folder 7-13)
  - Cost Factors for the Theater-Goer (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Costume Inventories - Accessories, [1971?] (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Costume Inventories - Men, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Costume Inventories - Women, [1971?] (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
  - Costume Inventories - Women, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Craft Avenue Blues - Song lyrics or poetry? (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Craft Avenue Theater - Revised Circuitry (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Crew Schedules, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Cultural Series, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Cultural Series - Mail Orders (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Curtain Going Up - Commemorative for Craft Avenue Theatre Reopening, [1952] (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Daily Activities Schedules, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dear Me, The Sky is Falling - Notes and memos (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Decals (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Deeds (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Delicate Balance - Notes and memos (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Donations, 1970-71 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Donations - Mrs. Drake Memorial (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Dramatic Arts Charges - Point Park College, 1967-1969 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Emergency Fund, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Employee addresses, June 1968 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - The Entertainer - Notes and memos (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - The Entertainer - Personal expenses (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Equipment Inventory - Ambridge Extension (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Esso Repertory Theater (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Experimental Productions - Budgets, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Fantasticks - Notes and memos (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Federal Tax Exemption (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Films - Attendance summary, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Films - Schedules, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Financial Report - Data, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Fire Drill instructions (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Frog Princess and the Witch - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Galileo - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Generation - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Goldilocks - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Guys and Dolls - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Gypsy - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hansel and Gretel - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Henry IV - Notes and memos (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Heywood-Wakefield (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - House Manager's reports, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
  - Insurance - Correspondence, 1967-68 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Insurance - Grant Kakel Ebbert (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Insurance - Miscellaneous, 1970-72 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Insurance - Notices of Injury/Accidents/Loss (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Insurance - Policies (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Insurance - Policies, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Internal Telephone List - Administration, 1971-1974? (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Inventories - Tools and equipment, 1969-1971 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Investor's Club (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Invitations to Playhouse parties (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Jack and the Beanstalk - Notes and memos (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - KDKA Editorial, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Land of the Dragon - Notes and memos (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Legal Opinions, Discussion topics, Correspondence, 1954-1964 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The Lesson - Notes and memos (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Licenses and permits (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Lighting - Inventory, September 1971 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Lion in Winter -- Rehearsal Schedules (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Liquor Control Board (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Liquor Control Board - Correspondence, 1958-1968 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Liquor Control Board - Executive Board questionnaires (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Liquor Control Board, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Liquor Licenses (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Mad Show - Notes and memos (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Mad Show - Contracts (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Man's a Man - Notes and memos (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Man of La Mancha - Notes and memos (Box 21, Folder 17-18)
  - Manual of passes and tickets, 1967-1969 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Mask and Wig Club (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Membership Reports, 1968-1971 (Box 22, Folder 3-6)
  - Membership - Solicitation letters, 1967-1972 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Membership - Summary, 1960-1970 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Membership - Order Receipt Ledgers, 1938-1957 (Box 23, Volume 1-18)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log - Playhouse Jr., 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log - Playhouse Jr., 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log - Playhouse Jr., 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log - Playhouse Jr., 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log - Playhouse Jr., 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1951-1952 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log - Playhouse Jr., 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Membership and Subscriptions Log, 1949-1950 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Miller plays (View from the Bridge and Memory of Two Mondays) - Rehearsal schedule (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Monthly summaries of operations, 1964-1967 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
  - Nassif - Hiatus (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - National Theatre of the Deaf (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Network Ticket Agency, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Non-Professional Affidavit (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Never Too Late - Notes and memos (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Notices of Determination - Unemployed compensation (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Nutcracker Ballet - Notes and memos, 1968-1969 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
  - Plan for the Pittsburgh Playhouse - 1974 and Beyond (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Plans to save the Playhouse, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Playhouse Association - Background (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Playhouse Association - President's Report Brochure (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Playhouse Building - Cut-away view (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Playhouse Club (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Playhouse Gallery - Pre 1957 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Playhouse Gallery - Exhibit lists, 1957-1959 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Playhouse Gallery - Exhibit lists, 1960-1967 (Box 28, Folder 17)